Smith College.
Smith College Archives
Duffy, Paula, 1967: In this oral history Paula "Polly" Duffy discusses how her love of the French language drew her to Smith with the promise of the JYA Paris program. She describes her first impressions at Smith, the house community she found in Hubbard House, and her experiences as someone coming from a family with a lower income than most Smithies. She goes on to talk about the dating scene and her participation as the vocalist in the first female, white, rock and roll group on campus, called the RhymeStones. She ends by discussing the opportunities afforded to her through the Smith network.
Field, Natalie, 1957: In this oral history, Natalie Field described the tradition of singing at Smith at events like Rally Day and the senior show, and sang several Smith songs. She also describes going to chapel every Wednesday, watching TV in Davis, the kingsmen, being at Smith during the space race, and house social regulations. Throughout, Field laments the loss of Smith traditions.
Freeman, Margaret, AMS 1963: In this oral history, Margaret Freeman describes her transition from University of Manchester, England to Smith College as one of the first group of the AMS Diploma Scholars. She describes the social life in Talbot House, the cultural differences, her surprise at the quality of Smith food and the practice of knitting in classes, and the ways Smith affected her life, particularly her intellectual confidence.
Friedman, Marcy, 1972: In this oral history, Marcy Friedman discusses her initial impression of Smith as conservative, her activism protesting the Vietnam War, and the changes she saw during her time at Smith. She comments on the racial dynamics and the silence surrounding lesbianism and same-sex relationships. She describes graduating as an "emerging radical second wave feminist," and her current position as a New York Supreme Court Justice.
Futterman, Marlene, 1958: In this oral history, Marlene Futterman describes choosing Smith because of its study abroad programs, studying in Geneva and subsequently going into the Foreign Service after graduating, and gaining confidence at Smith.
Gleason, Sandra, 1967: In this oral history, Sandra Gleason describes becoming an economics major, coming from a military family, living in Capen House, her housemothers, the traditions of mountain day and Rally day, her experience as a research assistant, the atmosphere of acceptance and open-mindedness at Smith, the benefits of the women's college experience, and her career in the academic world. RESTRICTED TO THE SMITH COMMUNITY
Group Interview, Class of 1957, Gail Richards Blunt; Ann Loomis Jesse; Elizabeth Mayor; Joan Millspaugh; Judy Oksner: In this oral history, Gail Richards Blunt, Ann Loomis Jesse, Elizabeth Mayor, Joan Millspaugh, and Judy Oksner describe what it was like to be at Smith during the 1950s, their relationships with their housemothers, knitting during classes, the dating scene, expectations for them when they graduated in terms of marriage and work, and where their lives have taken them since leaving Smith.
Group Interview, Class of 1982, Caroline Ely, Winn Gilmore, Sue Marcoux: In this oral history Caroline Ely, Winn Gilmore, and Susan Marcoux discuss their decisions to come to Smith, the differences between the Smith and Northampton lesbian scenes, Hover and Tenney Houses as epicenters of lesbian culture at Smith, their experiences in Lesbian Alliance, homophobia and racial tension on campus, and the tensions in the lesbian communities at Smith. RESTRICTED TO THE SMITH COMMUNITY
Habib, Mary Ann Savage, 1962: In this oral history, Mary Ann Savage Habib describes struggling through her first year, the dating scene, seeing Martin Luther King Jr. speak at Helen Hills Hills Chapel, her decision to move to California after graduating, and working at the National Union Catalog of Manuscript Collections.
Hussey, Danielle, 2002: In this oral history, Danielle Hussey describes how she found out about Smith from a high school English teacher, how she transferred from University of Vermont after her freshman year, her house community in Morrow House, the atmosphere of intellectual rigor, her participation in Peer Sexuality Educators (PSE) and other clubs, how the campus reacted to 9/11, and the importance of Ruth Simmons to her and the Smith Community in general.
Kanner, Ellen Kipnis, 1967: In this oral history, Ellen Kipnis Kanner describes her experience at Smith as a Jewish student, her study abroad in Spain, and a love of Smith College that continues years later.
Lewis, Brenda, 1967: In this oral history, Brenda Lewis describes her class as the last traditional class, comments upon the changes that took place during her tenure at Smith, and discusses her success in the world of business after graduating.
Long, Jerri Pantages, 1967: In this oral history, Jerri Pantages Long describes arriving at Smith from California, living in Parson for one year and then Tenney House for three years. She talks about Mountain Day and May Day traditions and the importance of a women's school.
Marcoux, Sue, 1982: In this oral history, Susan Marcoux describes living in Albright House for two years, going abroad in Germany, living in Hover House for her senior year, the lesbian scene at Smith, her work with Lesbian Alliance, and building an intellectual Smith community in San Francisco after graduating.
Nawara, Lucille, 1962: In this oral history, Lucille Nawara describes coming to Smith as a legacy student, her fear of posture pictures, coming from an artistic family and deciding to study art and music at Smith, feeling out of place in high school but comfortable at Smith, struggling through astronomy class, living in Tenney House and having President Mendenhall over for dinner, traditions like Mountain Day and regulations in the houses, the positive aspects of taking phys ed, and the confidence and analytical skills that Smith gave her as she continued on as an art professor and landscape designer.
Pepper, Francie Garber, 1962: In this oral history, Francie Pepper describes shattering her high school teacher's expectations by not only going to Smith but succeeding as well. She discusses coming from a long line of strong women, participating in sports while at Smith, studying abroad in Madrid, going to secretarial school and using her Spanish to get top jobs, raising money for the YWCA, and working on social issues like birth control, domestic violence, and trafficking.
Roberts, Paula, 1967: In this oral history, Paula Roberts discusses her political consciounsness starting at a young age, and how it grew and developed at Smith. She describes interning with Congressman Conte and Project Cornerstone, an experience that developed her understanding of racism. After leaving Smith, she talks about becoming a welfare caseworker and going to Law school.
Sargentini, Monica Ricci, AMS 1987: In this oral history, Monica Ricci Sargentini contrasts her education experience in Italy with Smith, specifically in regard to classes and social expectations. She talks about her academic interest in language and American literature, interests that drew her to the AMS Diploma Program. She ends her interview with a discussion about the value of women's colleges in general and the American approach to life.
2013: Narrators and class year
Barone, Jennifer, 2008: In this oral history, Jennifer Barone recalls political and social justice issues around race, sexual orientation and class on campus during her time at Smith and the student and administration response to those issues. She reflects on finding her voice at Smith and speaks about how she feels returning to Smith for reunion helps graduates stay connected to the sense of empowerment they experienced here. RESTRICTED TO THE SMITH COMMUNITY/NO ONLINE ACCESS
Boutin, Christine, 1988: In this oral history, recorded on the occasion of her 25th reunion, Christine Boutin speaks about the importance of lifelong friendships which began at Smith and remembers Smith traditions, including Thursday night candlelight suppers and Friday teas. She recalls social justice activism on campus, including participation in the College Hall divestiture sit-in as well as challenges like experiencing class differences in the student body.
Brassord, Lia, 1983: In this oral history, Lia Brassord, who has attended nearly every reunion since graduation, discusses the importance of that experience in her life. She reflects on the intergenerational bonds she has witnessed at Smith and the importance of the underlying qualities that cross those and other boundaries among Smithies.
Brickman, Ravelle, 1958: In this oral history Ravelle Brickman observes the changes she has seen on the Smith campus over the years, including the growing diversity of the student body. She reflects on her political activism at Smith and other highlights of her college years, including as a columnist for The Sophian and her role in founding of the Grecourt Review that published writers including Sylvia Plath.
Budd, Ruth, 1958: In this oral history, Ruth Budd recalls seeing Smith for the first time when she arrived alone as a first-year from Colorado. She speaks of the important role of women's colleges and remembers her junior year abroad in Geneva in 1956, during the Hungarian Revolution, and the life-long friendship that began during that experience.
Callahan, Kara, 1988: In this oral history, Kara Callahan discusses the deep connection she feels with Smith and the importance of attending a women's college. She expresses a delight in traditions like Convocation and Rally Day as formative in giving students a sense of what it means to be a "Smith woman."
Campen, Elizabeth, 1958: In this oral history, Elizabeth Campen reflects on the house culture at Smith which, in the 1950s, included house mothers. She recalls fondly traditions which no longer exist on campus, including Wednesday chapel. Campen talks about the importance of the legacy of a Smith education, the confidence that Smithies can do anything.
Dellerson, Alexandra, 2008: In this oral history, Alexandra Dellerson speaks about the importance of Smith's challenging academic environment as well as the open discussions of gender and sexuality. She recalls political and social issues on campus, including race and the presence of transgender students on campus and how the energy generated by that political climate contributed to her college experience. RESTRICTED TO THE SMITH COMMUNITY
Dwyer, Carol, 1958: In this oral history, Carol Dwyer reflects on the changes she has seen take place at Smith, the importance of the friendships she made in her house, and the opportunities for travel and exploration that accompanied her Junior Year abroad.
Dybwad, Barbara, 1998: In this oral history Barbara Dybwad speaks about the powerful effect of the Smith network in her life. She discusses the Smithenpoofs and the central role that group played in her college experience. She recalls classes that enriched her life as well as the unique experience and the camaraderie that developed during finals exams and the importance for her of the seriousness with which students approach academics at Smith.
Elliott, Susan, 1958: In this oral history, Susan Elliot, returning on the occasion of her 55th reunion, reflects on the importance of friendships formed through Smith's house culture and remembers house activities including playing bridge after supper with housemates. She recalls a meeting with a Smith advisor that lead to her to a new recruitment program that IBM had launched for women and how that became the foundation for her future business success.
Engeman, Martha Clough, 1983: In this oral history, done with classmate Nancy Hutchens Reif on the occasion of their 30th reunion, the women discuss how their meeting as freshmen lead to a lifetime relationship as best friends. They recall traveling to Paris together, including visiting the Smith office. They also reflect on the importance of Smith traditions, including Friday tea and Thursday night dinners. They recall political controversy on campus, such as an outcry against Jeane Kirkpatrick delivering the commencement address, as well as being on campus during the assassinations of Anwar Sadat and the murder of John Lennon. RESTRICTED TO THE SMITH COMMUNITY/NO ONLINE ACCESS
Franks, Rosalie Horne, 1958: In this oral history, Rosalie Horne Franks talks about why she has attended every Smith reunion since graduation in 1958. She discusses her experience of entering Smith at 16 as well as her observations of how Smith has changed, including the growing diversity of the student body and the global nature of the curriculum and the student population.
Gordon, Feivel, 2004, and Erica Hieggelke, 2003: In this oral history, Feivel Gordon and Erica Hieggelke, who met as first-years, reflect with candor and humor on their evolution as a couple. Feivel discusses his own process of self-discovery while at Smith and they speak candidly about the issue of transsexual students attending all-women's schools. They also recall being together on 9/11 and the aftermath of that trauma on campus.
Greer, Margaret Miller, 1978: In this oral history, Margaret Miller Greer speaks about the critical role that the self-confidence she acquired during her Smith years played in helping her meet future challenges. She recalls favorite Smith traditions, including tea and vespers, the importance of lifelong friendships she formed at Smith and wise words from Jill Kerr Conway.
Griffith, Theanne, 2008: In this oral history, Theanne Griffith speaks of choosing to attend Smith because of its neuroscience program, her involvement with the Black Students Alliance and the Smith Democrats, as well as the Underrepresented Science Students group on campus. She speaks of the overall importance of maintaining a diverse student population and how her experiences with issues of diversity at Smith prepared her for her future.
Harmon, Jennifer Lynn: In this oral history, Jennifer Harmon reflects on her experience as a woman of color at Smith, the benefits of the Bridge program, political issues on campus around race and sexual orientation during her years on campus, and the importance of her house community in her Smith experience. NO ONLINE ACCESS
Harris, Ali, 2008: In this oral history, Ali Harris speaks about treasured Smith traditions, including Friday tea, which provided a space for her and her housemates to detach from the pressure of academic life, pause and reflect, and enjoy each other socially. She speaks of the a commitment to community which she learned at Smith. She also recalls the mentors she met at Smith and the important role that mentorship played in her Smith life and beyond.
Hector, Allison, 2003: In this oral history, Allison Hector discusses the political environment during her college years, including the Iraq War and being on campus during the attack on the World Trade Center on 9/11 which occurred only weeks before she embarked on her junior year abroad. She recalls the importance of being with her Smith family during that difficult period and some memorable events, including Madeline Albright delivering her class's commencement address.
Hemingson, Celeste, 1963: In this oral history, Celeste Hemingson recalls the backdrop of political activism that marked her time at Smith, including student sit-ins to integrate the lunch counter at the Northampton Woolworths. She observes how her Smith experience gave her a love of learning and the self-confidence to pursue her passions, including becoming a priest.
Hieggelke, Erica, 2003, and Feivel Gordon, 2004: In this oral history, Erica Hieggelke and Feivel Gordon, who met as first years, reflect with candor and humor on their evolution as a couple which included Feivel's transition after graduation. Feivel discusses his own process of self-discovery while at Smith. They also recall being together on 9/11 and the aftermath of that trauma on campus.
Hudson, Julia, 2008: In this oral history, Julia Hudson talks about her views on Smith traditions, particularly Convocation, and the importance of the school's house culture, especially in formation of strong, lasting friendships. She discusses the way political thinking was developed in conversation with other Smithies and how issues of race, religion and sex were all part of the conversation.
Kestenbaum, Toni, 1963: In this oral history Toni Kestenbaum, who has attended every reunion since graduation, speaks of the affirming importance of this gathering. She also reflects on the changes she has witnessed over the years, including the diversity of the student body and an openness to sexual identity differences. She attributes her successful career in finance and business to the foundation she received at Smith.
Kohlbry, Cindy, 1978: In this oral history, Cindy Kohlbry recalls her love of Smith's theater department and the professors who made long-lasting impressions on her life. She reflects on some of the extra-curricular activities which shaped her Smith experience, including performing with the Smithenpoofs and the enduring friendships which were formed in that singing group.
Kolar, Alix, 1998: In this oral history, Alix Kolar speaks about the unique environment on the Smith campus and the foundation in critical thinking and breadth of interests that her Smith education provided. She recalls her favorite Smith traditions, including Friday teas, which remain important. NO ONLINE ACCESS
Korgen, Susan, 1983: In this oral history Susan Korgen, who is back on campus for her 25th reunion, reflects on her decision to go to Smith and speaks about her experience as a scholarship student and the class and racial differences she observed in the student body. She speaks about the influence going to Smith has had on her career, including a foundation of self-confidence that she attributes to the even playing field she that Smith created. NO ONLINE ACCESS
Laskin, Lisa Lauterbach, 1988: In this oral history, Lisa Lauterbach Laskin, whose mother was Smith Class of 1957, reflects on the way Smith has changed since her mother's years. She talks about her favorite tradition, Mountain Day, and the pleasure of spontaneity that it taught her.
Lehmann, Kate, 1978: In this oral history, Kate Lehmann recalls the Women's Movement and lesbian activism as significant pieces of the political backdrop during her Smith years, as well as her experience living in Greer Street rooming house. She speaks of the many ways Smith prepared her for the future by helping her develop analytical thinking and self-confidence.
Leyhow, Sharon, 1973: In this oral history, Sharon Leyhow recalls the political climate during her years at Smith, including student protests against the Vietnam War and other events and issues. She recalls her involvement with the Black Students Alliance and their activism to bring African-American Studies to Smith, and affect other changes. RESTRICTED TO THE SMITH COMMUNITY
Lober, Lori, 1983: In this oral history, Lori Lober speaks of feminism and its role in her Smith experience, including activism around the Women's Resource Center and the founding of Take Back the Night, as well as rape counseling and Lesbian Alliance workshops, and recalls stories of her experience as part of the Jewish Students Alliance. She credits her Smith education with her ability to reason, make a cogent argument and write effectively. NO ONLINE ACCESS
Maranuk, Allison, 2008: In this oral history, Allison Maranuk, speaks of how her activism at Smith prepared her for her career. She recalls the politically-charged climate during her Smith years, four years which began during the Bush-Kerry election, included the recession and the Iraq War, and came to an end with graduation in the year of President Obama's election. RESTRICTED TO THE SMITH COMMUNITY/NO ONLINE ACCESS
Mark, Leslie, 1983: In this oral history, Leslie Mark, who serves on the Smith Board of Directors, discusses her strong connection to the college. She speaks of the continuing importance of the Smith network in her life and the local alumnae chapters she's been a part of.
McKenzie, Leslie, 1968: In this oral history, Leslie McKenzie, a philosophy of religion major, recalls the professors and classes that made strong marks on her life and tells stories of unique teaching moments which she has never forgotten. She also recalls the difference that living in a small house made in her college experience.
Moffett, Jane, 1954: In this oral history, Jane Moffett recalls the extraordinary caliber of Smith's Art History Department which became the center of her life during her college years and beyond. She relates stories that shaped her worldview, including a conversation with Ruth Simmons that changed her life.
Morales, Lisa, AC, 1988: In this oral history, Lisa Morales speaks of her unique path to Smith and challenges faced by many Ada Comstock Scholars. Morales speaks of attending Smith for three years with as the mother of a young son. She recalls bringing her mother to her first Illumination Night and the importance of that and other experiences for them both.
Moses, Claire Goldberg, 1963: In this oral history Claire Goldberg Moses reflects on the occasion of the 50th class reunion. She speaks of the important role the house culture played in her college experience and on the central role her Junior Year abroad in Paris played in her life. She recalls a progressive political environment at Smith, which included Civil Rights demonstrations in front of the Northampton Woolworth building.
O'Bryant, Camille, 1983: In this oral history, Camille O'Bryant speaks about the critical role that athletics played in her Smith career and about discovering later the historic role Smith played in women's sports. She reflects on the people who helped her overcome the challenges Smith presented her with, including Jill Kerr Conway, and how that experience instilled in her the importance of giving back.
Ouelette, Eileen, 1958: In this oral history, Dr. Eileen Ouellette speaks from the perspective of her 55th reunion week. She recalls the preparation she received at Smith which allowed her to go on to Harvard Medical School and a career that has combined medicine and social justice activism, including national advocacy on behalf of victims of Hurricane Katrina, particularly, children. NO ONLINE ACCESS
Pilvin, Barbara, 1973: In this oral history, Barbara Pilvin relates memories of Smith professors who made important and lasting impressions on her. She recalls a life-changing year abroad and talks about the importance of reunion and why she has only missed one since her graduation.
Pyun, Catherine, 1988: In this oral history Catherine Pyun speaks during her 25th reunion weekend. She discusses the role that her first visit to campus played her decision to apply to Smith and of making lifelong friends, including through her participation in sports. She also discusses the importance of having an engineering and science program for women at Smith. RESTRICTED TO THE SMITH COMMUNITY/NO ONLINE ACCESS
Rabin, Eva, 2008: In this oral history Eva Rabin discusses the pull that attending Smith reunions has for her and her friends. She recalls her decision to go to Smith after attending an alumnae reception in California and her continuing admiration for Smith graduates. Rabin recalls her junior year abroad in Scotland and the ways in which that experience changed her future.